Latino Youth Community History Project Oral History Project OHP005
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Latino Youth Community History Project Oral History Project
1981-1982
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Latin American Youth Center
OHP005
2.75 Linear feet
3 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: Indexes Materials in this series include indexes for most interviews. Series 2: Interviews Materials in this series include master and patron access copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are two copies of each audio cassette except for 05-05. There are no audio recordings for 05-03 and 05-20.
Biographical / Historical
The Latin American Youth Center was founded in 1968 to address the absence of services for the emerging Latino community offering educational and vocational activities in after school and in the summer programs.
Custodial History
The Latin American Youth Center conducted the interviews between 1981 and 1982 and transferred the tapes and indexes to the Library in 1983 as a condition of their grant with the National Endowment for the Humanities. There is no deed of gift for this collection.
Scope and Contents
From 1981 and 1982, the Latin American Youth Center in Washington, D.C. conducted approximately 47 oral history interviews with Latino community members, of which 24 were donated to the Library. The project's directors were Lisa Wheaton and Lesley Rankin-Hill. The project was funded by the National Endowment for the Humanities, and all interviews were conducted by high school students. Indexes are in English and Spanish; taped interviews are in Spanish. Collection contains notes on interviews and transcripts which were not transferred to the Library at the time of donation.
Oral History; Hispanic Americans
- Series 1: Indexes
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this series include indexes for most interviews.
  - Jasmin Garabito, 1982 March 28 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cristina Espinel, 1982 November 30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Frank Shaffer Corona, 1982 January 13 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Luis Rumbeaut, 1982 January 24 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Margarita Suarez, 1982 April 11 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Salvago Gustavo, 1982 April 13 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Antonio Leiva, 1981 November 25 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Lori Kaplan, 1982 March 9 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Candida Patino, 1982 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lucy Carvajal, 1981 December 15 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Davila Marcela, 1982 February 23 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Enrique Rivera, 1982 January 4 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Harry Struthers and Anne Houston, 1982 March 15 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Maria Elena Orego, 1982 March 30 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Arturo Silvester, 1982 April 6 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Sonia Gutierrez, 1982 April 17 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Viterbo Martinez, 1982 March 7 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Luis Gonzales, 1982 March 10 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Eddie Pardo, 1982 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Julio Alvarado, 1982 November 28 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Casilda Luna, 1982 February 16 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Lisa Wheaton, 1982 September 1 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Salazar Albertina, 1982 March 5 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Series 2: Interviews
  Materials in this series include master and patron access copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are two copies of each audio cassette except for 05-05. there are no audio recording for 05-03 and 05-20.
  - Jasmin Garabito, 1982 March 28 (Box 2, Folder 05-01)
  - Cristina Espinel, 1982 November 30 (Box 2, Folder 05-02)
  - Luis Rumbeaut, 1982 January 24 (Box 2, Folder 05-04)
  - Margarita Suarez, 1982 April 11 (Box 2, Folder 05-05)
  - Salvago Gustavo, 1982 April 13 (Box 2, Folder 05-06)
  - Antonio Leiva, 1981 November 25 (Box 2, Folder 05-07)
  - Lori Kaplan, 1982 March 9 (Box 2, Folder 05-08)
  - Candida Patino, 1982 April 14 (Box 2, Folder 05-09)
  - Lucy Carvajal, 1981 December 15 (Box 2, Folder 05-10)
  - Davila Marcela, 1982 February 23 (Box 2, Folder 05-11)
  - Enrique Rivera, 1982 January 4 (Box 2, Folder 05-12)
  - Harry Struthers and Anne Houston, 1982 March 15 (Box 2, Folder 05-13)
  - Maria Elena Orego, 1982 March 30 (Box 2, Folder 05-14)
  - Arturo Silvester, 1982 April 6 (Box 2, Folder 05-15)
  - Sonia Gutierrez, 1982 April 17 (Box 2, Folder 05-16)
  - Viterbo Martinez, 1982 March 7 (Box 2, Folder 05-17)
  - Luis Gonzales, 1982 March 10 (Box 2, Folder 05-18)
  - Eddie Pardo, 1982 June 20 (Box 2, Folder 05-19)
  - Casilda Luna, 1982 February 16 (Box 2, Folder 05-21)
  - Lisa Wheaton, 1982 September 1 (Box 3, Folder 05-22)
  - Salazar Albertina, 1982 March 5 (Box 3, Folder 05-23)